{"source_url": "apstylebook.com/ask_the_editors/50310", "question": "from South Carolina, on Nov. 22, 2025 Any guidance for articles that talk about beef grades? For example, Restaurant X serves a selection of choice and prime steaks. Should \"choice\" and \"prime\" be capitalized in this usage? Thanks in advance!", "answer": "If you need to use the terms, capitalize them. That way, people are clear this is a ranking by an agency, not your own feelings about how the beef rates. (If you can, use more specific terms. These feel like industry jargon, and most audiences probably don't really know what they mean)."}
{"source_url": "apstylebook.com/ask_the_editors/50308", "question": "from Washington, District of Columbia, on Nov. 21, 2025 Two legal questions on ChatGPT and AP Stylebook: 1. In searching ChatGPT, it appears there is a function where someone can ask AI to check a document using AP Style. Is that a sanctioned tool AP has endorsed? 2. Since the AP Stylebook is a paid subscription, are there legal ramifications for asking a large language model (LLM) to use AP Style in reviewing a document?", "answer": "We don't recommend using AI tools to check for AP Style. It is not sanctioned or endorsed by AP, and we have found that many tools miss mistakes, introduce errors and sometimes just make things up. Also, the AP Stylebook Online is updated in real time, so you will always have the newest, best advice. That's not true of many LLMs."}
{"source_url": "apstylebook.com/ask_the_editors/50305", "question": "on Nov. 20, 2025 Is style now different for financial reporting regarding \"healthcare\"? Or is AP going to that construction? Almost all the business reporting AP stories about health care are now using that construction.", "answer": "We have not changed the guidance, but it is under review. Stay tuned!"}
{"source_url": "apstylebook.com/ask_the_editors/50299", "question": "from Ohio, on Nov. 19, 2025 Any thoughts about the appropriateness of \"underage girls\"? In my opinion, it normalizes sexist / harmful constructs in the manner of \"child porn.\" I'd use \"girls\" or \"children.\" Thanks!", "answer": "I agree - \"children\" or \"girls\" or \"teen girls\" are specific terms that don't trivialize criminal acts. In fact, that's why we added guidance in our criminal justice chapter in 2024 recommending writers avoid the term \"child pornography.\" Here's the latest guidance: child pornography Generally avoid the terms child pornography and child porn. Use them only when essential in direct quotations or excerpts from documents. Instead, describe such charges or allegations as possessing (or producing) child sexual abuse images or possessing (or producing) child sexual abuse material, including in headlines. See child sexual abuse images for more guidance."}
{"source_url": "apstylebook.com/ask_the_editors/50297", "question": "from Washington, District of Columbia, on Nov. 18, 2025 Which is correct/preferred? I am granting you a 2-hour dismissal. OR I am granting you a two-hour dismissal.", "answer": "\"I am granting you a two-hour dismissal.\" In our numerals entry, you can find this guidance under the subhead TIMES."}
{"source_url": "apstylebook.com/ask_the_editors/50293", "question": "from Denver, Colorado, on Nov. 17, 2025 When quoting someone, is it a rule that you should use: \"quote,\" Title Name said. Or: \"quote,\" said, Title Name. Or is either acceptable? I've tried reading the sections on attribution and quotations and have struggled to find the correct answer.", "answer": "There are multiple acceptable options. I usually decide depending on the length of the person's title. Here's how each could look (all of these are correct): \"We recommend using this term,\" said AP Stylebook Editor Anna Jo Bratton. \"We recommend using that term,\" said Pia Sarkar, a longtime member of the AP Stylebook Committee. \"We had hoped to win another term,\" Mayor Eric Adams said."}
{"source_url": "apstylebook.com/ask_the_editors/50292", "question": "from Plainfield, New Jersey, on Nov. 17, 2025 Does AP have a style for end notes? If so, do we abbreviate the month in an end note? Thank you.", "answer": "If you are following AP style for the body copy, use it for end notes, too. Here's the relevant guidance on months: Capitalize the names of months in all uses. When a month is used with a specific date, abbreviate only Jan., Feb., Aug., Sept., Oct., Nov. and Dec. Spell out when using alone, or with a year alone."}
{"source_url": "apstylebook.com/ask_the_editors/50288", "question": "from Lakewood, Ohio, on Nov. 16, 2025 Would you capitalize \"the\" in The City Club or The Ohio State University?", "answer": "I would not. I do realize \"The Ohio State University\" it's somewhat of a slogan, with the emphasis on \"the.\" But in non-promotional copy, I'd use proper style."}
{"source_url": "apstylebook.com/ask_the_editors/50285", "question": "from California, on Nov. 13, 2025 When you're listing the day and times when something is always open, would you say: Monday, 9:00 a.m.—12:00 p.m. OR Mondays, 9:00 a.m.—12:00 p.m.", "answer": "Monday, 9-11 a.m. (Singular, and shorter. See the times entry in the Stylebook)."}
{"source_url": "apstylebook.com/ask_the_editors/50282", "question": "from Atlanta, Georgia, on Nov. 13, 2025 What is AP's CURRENT official guidance of the use of Department of War vs. Department of Defense. I'm getting conflicting information from colleagues about what they've been finding on AP.com.", "answer": "We advise using the legal name, which is currently Department of Defense. If Congress changes the name to Department of War, we would use that term. It might be helpful to include in current copy that President Trump's preference is Department of War, and that many federal documents and agencies use that moniker."}
{"source_url": "apstylebook.com/ask_the_editors/50279", "question": "from Lee's Summit, Missouri, on Nov. 11, 2025 Hi AP. My original sentence in question is this: This legislation repeals language related to the executive partial veto that allowed for automatic, indefinite $325 per-pupil funding increases. Because we're looking at a compound modifier situation that explains the types of funding increases, I want to confirm this is the correct way to hyphenate that phrase: This legislation repeals language related to the executive partial veto that allowed for automatic, indefinite $325-per-pupil funding increases.", "answer": "I would only use one hyphen in this case, as in your first example."}
{"source_url": "apstylebook.com/ask_the_editors/50278", "question": "from San Francisco, California, on Nov. 11, 2025 Would you keep the hyphens in this description: \"... business leaders who range from data-curious to data-savvy...\"?", "answer": "I'd skip the hyphens. I don't think they're needed for clarity."}
{"source_url": "apstylebook.com/ask_the_editors/50273", "question": "on Nov. 10, 2025 Does AP recommend capitalizing state laws? For example: The motorist was issued several citations for vehicle and traffic law violations. The suspect was charged with criminal possession of a controlled substance in the third degree.", "answer": "No, we don't recommend capitalizing the laws. In fact, we would encourage using plain language whenever possible, in addition to or instead of wording that might confuse readers."}
{"source_url": "apstylebook.com/ask_the_editors/50272", "question": "from Ventura, California, on Nov. 8, 2025 Is it appropriate to use \"according to\" when referring to something said by a person? Some sources indicate that \"according to John Doe\" is incorrect, while \"according to the report\" is correct.", "answer": "Yes, that's fine. Simpler still to just use \"said.\""}
{"source_url": "apstylebook.com/ask_the_editors/50269", "question": "from Washington, District of Columbia, on Nov. 7, 2025 Is the comma necessary after 2020? They worked from Jan. 1, 2020, to Jan. 1, 2023.", "answer": "Yes."}
{"source_url": "apstylebook.com/ask_the_editors/50268", "question": "from Boca Raton, Florida, on Nov. 6, 2025 Hoping for final guidance on this one: \" choke hold \" or \" chokehold.\" Though an Oct. 5, 2023, response indicates a preference for \"the one-word version,\" the Chapter C entry of the Stylebook has it as two words. Thank you in advance!", "answer": "Strangely, I don't see any current entry for either. Perhaps you are looking at an old stylebook, and it was dropped at some point? We do sometimes drop words if we see they don't come up a lot, and just defer to our dictionary, which is Merriam-Webster. And in this case, the dictionary says choke hold, so I'll defer to them and delete that Ask the Editor response. Thanks for noticing!"}
{"source_url": "apstylebook.com/ask_the_editors/50262", "question": "from Issaquah, Washington, on Nov. 4, 2025 When I search for a prefix, sometimes the Prefixes entry is the last result: for instance, \"super-\". In this case, the Super entry is a top search result, but the entry does not address \"super\" used as a prefix. Because the Prefixes search result is below so many other irrelevant results, it's easy to miss (and easy to assume it's not a prefix covered in the Prefixes entry). Will you please fix this? Perhaps give each prefix an entry that directs the user to the Prefixes entry?", "answer": "Thanks for this suggestion - we will look into how to improve this situation."}
{"source_url": "apstylebook.com/ask_the_editors/50257", "question": "from Pahrump, Nevada, on Nov. 1, 2025 Headline question: I've been seeing these constructions that read to me as comma splices. Is this acceptable under AP headline style, or should we rewrite with an em dash, semicolon or period? I've been updating them to that. Examples: X is in the top 10 best cities in the US, see where X's first frost is significantly delayed, here's how it affects wildlife, recreation I would like to create a consistent rule if there is one, or redirect people to the correct format. Thanks!", "answer": "I agree, this is poor sentence construction. I'd use a period."}
{"source_url": "apstylebook.com/ask_the_editors/50256", "question": "from Arizent - Financial Planning, on Oct. 31, 2025 If someone tacks on the word \"right\" at the end of a sentence, what's the best way to handle that? For example: \"We all need to get along, right?\" Or is it technically two sentences — one a declaration, and the question follows? \"We all need to get along. Right?\"", "answer": "I'd use the comma. It more closely follows the way I assume the person said it."}
{"source_url": "apstylebook.com/ask_the_editors/50255", "question": "from Washington, District of Columbia, on Oct. 30, 2025 I work for a non-profit organization that deals extensively in legislation, and we reoutinely publish newsletters for our members and press releases in accordance with AP Style. I understand that full bill names are not usually spelled out in favor of a longer explanation of what the legislation/bill would do. How would bill names and numbers be written if it was a requirement, as it is for our organization? We often reference bills that are in congress as well as those that have already become law.", "answer": "Follow the style used by the legislative body."}
{"source_url": "apstylebook.com/ask_the_editors/50254", "question": "from ALBANY, New York, on Oct. 30, 2025 \"Correction officer\" is the official title for those who work in security positions in state prisons and county jails. Is \"guard\" acceptable or is it similar to referring to police officers \"cops,\" which AP says should be avoided in news stories and is considered derogatory.", "answer": "Guards is fine as a general term. It's has the added benefit of being much more conversational than \"correction officer.\""}
{"source_url": "apstylebook.com/ask_the_editors/50253", "question": "from Walnut Creek, California, on Oct. 29, 2025 There still seems to be more debate on FAQ vs. FAQs. I have been using FAQ to refer to a webpage of questions on a particular topic. I would use FAQs if I was saying something like: Check out our FAQs on Apples and Oranges. Can you settle this debate, here in 2025?", "answer": "We recommend FAQ (no \"s\") in the singular. Add the \"s\" in plural uses, to be clear it's two different FAQs."}
{"source_url": "apstylebook.com/ask_the_editors/50250", "question": "from Pennsylvania, on Oct. 28, 2025 Hi Anna Jo! I'm stuck on if or how I should spell out the numerals in the following sentence where we're saying \"four out of five women.\" My inclination is to spell out both numerals and capitalize \"Four\" following the colon since it's not a traditional fraction and both are below 10. (Separately, if it were \"nine out of 10 women,\" would you use mixed numerals?) Thanks for your help! \"They are not alone: 4/5 women without access to financial accounts live in such areas.\"", "answer": "That's correct written out, \"four out of five.\" And I agree, I would capitalize following the colon since it starts a complete sentence. On \"nine out of 10,\" use the mixed numerals."}
{"source_url": "apstylebook.com/ask_the_editors/50248", "question": "from Vernon Hills, Illinois, on Oct. 28, 2025 I can't find the entry on COBRA online. Does it still need to be spelled out as Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act?", "answer": "Use COBRA on first reference, then spell it out somewhere lower down. However, if you are writing for a non-U.S. audience, you should consider whether it's well-known. I'd probably add a short description on first reference, too."}
{"source_url": "apstylebook.com/ask_the_editors/50247", "question": "from Williamsport, Pennsylvania, on Oct. 28, 2025 Near-full or near full? No noun after it.", "answer": "No hyphen."}
{"source_url": "apstylebook.com/ask_the_editors/50244", "question": "from SOUTH MIAMI, Florida, on Oct. 26, 2025 Doesn't a phrase like \"motorsports lifestyle content agency\" need a hyphen for clarity somewhere? My vote is to hyphenate it like: \"motorsports-lifestyle content agency\" for clarity. What do you think? I just thought there was a rule for so many modifiers...", "answer": "You don't need the hyphen unless it can be misunderstood without one. I confess, I have no idea what a \"motorsports lifestyle content agency\" does, so depending on your audience, you might look for a more conversational term."}
{"source_url": "apstylebook.com/ask_the_editors/50222", "question": "from Williamsport, Pennsylvania, on Oct. 20, 2025 Holly Jolly Holiday Party -- is the formatting of Holly Jolly correct? No hyphen?", "answer": "No hyphen needed - I don't think anyone will be confused without it. Sounds like fun!"}
{"source_url": "apstylebook.com/ask_the_editors/50220", "question": "from Seattle, Washington, on Oct. 16, 2025 Hi. Would these bullets have periods? By themselves they’re fragments but following the lead in of “The conversation moved” they become full sentences. I lean toward yes but would love confirmation. Thanks! The conversation moved: From hypothetical to urgent From immigration to healthcare access From numbers to individuals", "answer": "I would not include a period, to follow the rule: \" Use no punctuation at the end of a single word or single phrase in each section of a list.\" (I do see your point - they complete the sentence that starts with \"The conversation moved...\" I'll add this to my list to reconsider with the Stylebook team)."}
{"source_url": "apstylebook.com/ask_the_editors/50215", "question": "from Gadsden, Alabama, on Oct. 15, 2025 When I searched for Boy Scouts, the Stylebook says that is the proper term. However, the organization formally changed its name to Scouting America in 2025. Do we just ignore their preferred name since most people know it as Boy Scouts?", "answer": "We need to update this entry now that the name has changed. Thanks for pointing it out! (In a news story, I would still say \"previously called the Boy Scouts,\" or \"more commonly known as the Boy Scouts,\" at least until people are familiar with the new name)."}
{"source_url": "apstylebook.com/ask_the_editors/50213", "question": "from Boulder, Colorado, on Oct. 15, 2025 Is copy editing one word or two? In the copy editor entry it is listed as two words, but I see it used as one word \"copyediting\" frequently.", "answer": "AP Style says two words, and Merriam-Webster agrees, although they do give copyeditor as a less common second usage."}
{"source_url": "apstylebook.com/ask_the_editors/21819", "question": "from Philadelphia, on June 11, 2014 Hello. What is AP's rule regarding ending sentences with a preposition? Your assistance is greatly appreciated.", "answer": "In AP usage, there's no objection to ending a sentence with a preposition."}
{"source_url": "apstylebook.com/ask_the_editors/23079", "question": "from Bellaire, Texas, on Oct. 21, 2014 What is the correct job title for someone who died while holding his or her last position? Would he forever be CEO or should he be referred to as former CEO?", "answer": "Use the formal title in reporting the death and thereafter until a replacement is named. Thereafter, the person who died can be described as the late CEO or CEO at the time of his death."}
{"source_url": "apstylebook.com/ask_the_editors/22726", "question": "from Austin, Texas, on Sept. 17, 2014 My Farm Credit colleagues and I were pondering whether to use figures or spell out numbers when using acres. It's also a discussion we often had in newsrooms when I worked for newspapers. I see on the Ask the Editor FAQs page that acres take figures, but it's not spelled out in the print edition of the stylebook. Can we make a plea for indicating that acres take figures in print edition under the acres, numerals and dimensions entries? For example, the dimensions entry refers to length, width, height and depth, but not to area, such as 1 acre.", "answer": "Confirming numerals for acreage, including 1 acre. We'll look into adding the example."}
{"source_url": "apstylebook.com/ask_the_editors/23000", "question": "from San Francisco, on Oct. 14, 2014 For stories such as car accidents the mention the vehicle name, such as a Toyota 4Runner, should the make or model be used on second reference?", "answer": "Use SUV on further reference, or other descriptive like sedan or coupe or pickup, as the case may be."}
{"source_url": "apstylebook.com/ask_the_editors/22751", "question": "from Jefferson City, Mo., on Sept. 19, 2014 I am working on a report and am confused if I should capitalize Master's of Public Health and Bachelor in Public Health. The bullet points in the report are: Number of graduates with a Master's of Public Health working in public health... Number of graduates with a Bachelor in Public Health working in public health... Also should this be Bachelor's? Thank you.", "answer": "CORRECTION: within a sentence, master's of public health... bachelor's in public health... Lowercase master's and bachelor's with the specialty. However, the full degree name is capitalized: Master of Science, Bachelor of Arts."}
{"source_url": "apstylebook.com/ask_the_editors/23555", "question": "from Woodbridge, N.J., on Dec. 10, 2014 Does the earlier Ask the Editor answer about using \"road map\" as two words apply to the phrase when used in the abstract? For example, would road map be one or two words in \"Define core capabilities and a company roadmap for digital transformation\"? Thank you!", "answer": "Two words by the dictionary's second definition of road map: any set of directions, proposals, policies, etc., for achieving some objective."}
{"source_url": "apstylebook.com/ask_the_editors/22821", "question": "from Denver, on Sept. 27, 2014 In AP Style, can I use a dash to set off a complete sentence within another sentence? Example: Even the larger social and historical questions that shaped the Cold War - Can a nation be free and have community at the same time? - remain relevant for our communities today.", "answer": "If not overused, it's acceptable under the ABRUPT CHANGE section of the Stylebook's \"dash\" entry. However, the \"have community\" reference would be too vague or sweeping for summing up the Cold War."}
{"source_url": "apstylebook.com/ask_the_editors/22917", "question": "from Wilmette, Ill., on Oct. 7, 2014 An American news organization recently identified Emmanuel Macron of France as minister of economy. Probably a translation of ministre de l'economie. But in the past most news organizations have translated this as economics minister. Which is correct? Thanks.", "answer": "In AP stories from France, Economy Minister Emmanuel Macron."}
{"source_url": "apstylebook.com/ask_the_editors/23337", "question": "from Austin, Texas, on Nov. 16, 2014 I've been told by writing coaches and editors that when comparing figures (or percentages) from year to year, the newest one should go first. Example: Reports of car burglaries in Austin have dropped from 40 in 2013 to 64 in 2012. Is this AP style, too?", "answer": "Do you mean that reports of car burglaries in Austin dropped to 40 in 2013 from 64 in 2012? Comparisons are often written that way in AP stories."}
{"source_url": "apstylebook.com/ask_the_editors/22961", "question": "from Portland, Oregon, on Oct. 9, 2014 I see that you've got to a standardized style for the 2014 enterovirus outbreak: http://www.apstylebook.com/online/?do=ask_editor&id=26651. I'm curious for more detail on why you're opting for enterovirus-68, not -D68 (and why the hyphen, too). Is the 68 vs. D68 a distinction in ICTV vs. Baltimore viral classification systems, or is there another reason involved? Also, have you been able to pin down whether 68/D68 is considered a type, subtype, strain, etc. (well, depending on the preferred system of classification and whether it uses groups smaller than viral species)? Thanks!", "answer": "An AP story early in 2014 spelled it enterovirus-68. More recent AP stories on the outbreak have used enterovirus D68 or enterovirus 68. It's described as an uncommon strain of a very common family of viruses."}
